

JOLSNA V JOSE

918075543422

Kalkere, Bangalore 560043

inkedin.com/in/jolsna-v-jose-5a61b48b/

PROFILE

Dedicated professional with proven skills and experience in recruiting, staffing, vendor management and human resource management. Dependable with proven ability to succeed under pressure, deliver establish genuine excellence, and relationships. A team player with effective interpersonal communication skills and a strong work ethic. Four years of experience in Recruitment working with domain clients like Software, Financial, Telecom, and Banking. Successful in Sourcing, Screening, Validating, Salary Negotiation and Placement follow-up.

KEY SKILLS

- ☐ HR Policies & Procedures
- Talent Management
- □ Staff Recruitment & Retention
- ☐ Employee Relations
- Employee Engagement Programme
- □ Alternative Dispute Resolutions
- Orientation &Onboarding
- □ HRIS Technologies
- ☐ Training & Development
- Performance Management
- Organizational Development
- □ Oral & Written Communication
- ☐ MS Office (Word, Excel)
- □ Tally ERP

EDUCATION

- MBA in Human Resource & Marketing, Kannur University, Kerala, India-2013
- MSW in Medical & Psychiatry,
 M G University, Kerala, India-2010
- BSc Science, Kannur University, Kerala, India-2008

LANGUAGES

- English
- ☐ Hindi
- □ Tamil
- □ Malayalam

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Syban India: Global HR Services Provider–Bangalore, India. (07/2021-07/2022) IT Recruiter

Aquity Solutions India Pvt Ltd– Bangalore, India. (08/ 2019 -09/2020) $HR\ Executive$

Mansard Software Soluions Pvt Ltd –Bangalore, India. (11/2018 -08/2019)

HR Recruiter

Spectra HR Solutions- Bangalore, India. (01/2018-10/2018)

Ultraline Logistics & Freight Services- Doha , Qatar. (01/2016 - 10/2016) HR Frequency

WORK EXPERIENCE

Recruiter (Syban India

HR Recruiter

Recruiter (IT & Automotive)

Syban India: Global HR Services Provider—Bangalore, India 07/2021 – 07/2022

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- · Coordinating with hiring managers to identify staffing needs/Vacancy intake.
- Full cycle recruitment process from creating job descriptions, determining sourcing channels, screening, interview process, providing feedback to the candidates, offer acceptance, negotiations and on-boarding.
- Plan interview and selection procedures, including screening calls, assessments and in-person interviews.
- Design job descriptions and interview questions that reflect each position's requirements.
- Sourcing potential candidates through online channels (e.g., social platforms and professional networks).
- · Checking existing talent pool and employee referrals.
- Identifying the best talent, and analyzing each resume carefully, paying attention to the detail.
- · Conducting screening interview to weed out incompatible job applicants.
- Coordinating with hiring manager other team members to develop a successful recruitment function.
- Supporting hiring manager in making a data driven hiring decision.
- Providing feedback to the candidates.
- Keeping in touch with new hires during pre boarding period to keep them engaged and excited to get started.
- · Documentation of the new hires.
- Regularly checks in with the new employee while on boarding.

Skills worked for IT: Java/J2EE developer, C++ developer, .Net developer, Technical Architect, Automation Testing, Mobile Application Testing, UI Developer, AWS Developer, DevOps AWS,AWS Architect, Manual Testing, Software developer, Big Data Developer,Big Data Technical Architect, Go Lang Developer etc.

Skills worked for Automotive: Senior Configuration Engineer – Electromobility, System Design Engineer (Lead & Senior), Hardware Engineer (Senior& Junior), GM BMS-Electromobility, GM OppCharge Power Conversion, GM Software Cl/CD, GM ESS Control, Geometrical Architect - Virtual Builds, Verification Engineer (Senior & Lead)Epic Owner – Driver Security, Safety & Visibility etc.

HR Executive

Aquity Solutions India Pvt Ltd - Bangalore, India

08/2019 - 09/2020

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Recruitment and selection of candidates for interviews.
- Conduct pre- employment / reference checks for the experienced candidates who have been selected through the interview process.
- Liaison with team for Employee-Referral initiatives.
- Handles all on boarding and off boarding activities.
- Preparation of relevant letters to effect staff movements (appointment, resignation, transfers, confirmation and promotion)
- Scheduling induction and conduct the Induction programme.
- Monitor process compliance of team members.
- Administer HRIS system and updating employee employment records: hiring, transfer, promotion and Resignation.
- Taking care of Employee engagement activities and birthday celebration.
- Preparing weekly and monthly recruitment reports.
- Maintain the personal folders.
- Taking care of OU movement in respect to Departmental and Reporting changes.
- Handles employees Medical Insurance and claims processing.
- Interact with employees on a regular basis and maintain good employee relations.
- Preparation and initiate activities for the expansion of employee data bank.

N

HR Recruiter (IT & NON-IT)

Mansard Software Solutions Pvt Ltd -Bangalore, India

11/2018- 08/2019

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- · Sourcing of candidates through job portals, candidate's references, and internal data.
- Working closely with Hiring Managers/Project Managers to get detailed requirements along with meeting the deadlines for submissions of per requirements.
- Responsible for creating job postings, reviewing a high volume of resumes, conducting telephonic interviews, coordinating interviews with the clients, extending offers, negotiating salary and follow up and closing the positions.
- Evaluating the candidate's Communication skill, Reason for Job Change, Work experience, present and expected compensation, location/relocation information, work authorization status, Notice Period, availability for the interview etc.
- Attend standup meetings to update and discuss the Recruitment activities with the Recruitment Manager and plan the strategies to fulfill the roles.
- · Worked on profiles ranging from entry levels to mid seniors levels.
- · Taking regular feedback from the clients.

Skills worked for: Java/J2EE developer, C++ developer, .Net developer, Automation Testing, Mobile Application Testing, UI Developer, AWS Developer, Manual Testing, Software developer.



HR Recruiter (NON-IT)

Spectra HR Solutions, Freelancer - Bangalore, India

01/2018 - 10/2018

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Understanding the job description of the client and develop sourcing strategies for the same.
- Sourcing the CVs of candidates through job portals, social media and references.
- Short listing the profiles by validating them on their experience and interest on the role.
- Making calls to shortlisted candidates.
- Scheduling interviews of shortlisted candidates and sending them to the Hiring Manager.
- Sharing feedback to the candidates.

HR Executive Ultraline Logistics & Freight Services - Doha, Qatar 01/2016 - 10/2016

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Perform and/or direct day to day administrative tasks.
- Maintain and file all records in accordance with company procedure.
- Responsible to create HR policies and procedures with senior management.
- Confer with management and staff coordinating all the activities.
- Ensure to process orders and on-time delivery of all the shipments to companies.
- Providing an enabling workplace by effective and timely resolution of employee grievances.
- Ensuring compliance to policies & code of conduct by the employees.
- Conducting induction and orientation programs for new joiners